Amanamabasi Akpan



amanamabasiakpan@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/amanamabasi-akpan



+2349077016503



https://www.amanams.com

Summary

Tech-driven Frontend Developer with 2+ years of practical knowledge in coding / designing web applications and interfaces.

With work-ready proficiency in HTML5, JavaScript and CSS, I have built applications and websites using Flutter, React & Bootstrap. Also equipped with working knowledge of Versions control system (GIT), Wordpress and UX / UI Designing, I am capable of handling project lifecycles from conceptualization to rollout.

I am eager to use my skills and strengths to build and develop software solutions in an environment that helps me advance in my career by building my skills with practical and relevant industry experience.

Experience

iRUN Frontend Developer / UX & UI Designer

iRUN Technology

May 2021 - Present (9 months +)

- Create wireframes, storyborards, sitemaps, mockups, and prototypes of site/app designs and convert them into the real, usable interfaces
- Utilizing multiple markup, styling and programming languages to write clean and reuaable codes for web pages such as Javascript, HTML & CSS
- Perform regular site maintenance and optimization of web pages for maximum speed, scalability, troubleshoot and fix bugs and errors.
- Collaborate with a multidisciplinary team of Web Designers, Back-end Developers, Project Managers, System Analysts to complete projects
- Build web solutions using Bootstrap, Flutter and react.
- Set design guidelines, best practices, and standards
- Stay up to date with the latest UI trends, techniques, and technologies

П

Executive Assistant / Brand Strategist

Thesaurus Gardens Limited (Real-Estate)

Sep 2019 - Jul 2021 (1 year 11 months)

- Create wireframes, sitemaps, mockups, brochures, illuatrations and various multimedia contents for company website and social media.
- Utilizing multiple markup, styling and programming languages to write clean and reuaable codes for web pages such as Javascript, HTML & CSS

- Develop and implement social media brand strategies, campaigns, and plans to build brand awareness and growth
- Involved in product concept design to implementation of Caribbean Lake City Estate.
- Create and maintain sales pipelines, follow up and report, Conduct site inspection and intimate potential clients on products and services.
- Supervising artisans and staff to achieve company goals and standards.

Education



University of Uyo

Bachelor of Urban & Regional Planning - B.URP, Urban and Regional Planning 2014 - 2019

Excelled in Land Use planning and detailing, including Physical and Software Modelling

Presentation of Proposals on Physical Planning strategies and development

Application of AutoCAD and Other Software in designs and Presentation.

Conducted a Research on The role of Government in Recreational Development exposing loopholes and bottlenecks in the sector.

Student Body President.



International Management & Finance Institute, ICT Academy. Uyo.

Diploma, Advanced IT Skills

2012 - 2013

Basic to Advanced use of Microsoft office suites and other fundamental computer software.

Specialization:

- 1. Software Maintenance & IT Support
- 2. Visual Design (Web & Graphics)
- 3. Networking and data collaborations
- 4. Digital Marketing

Licenses & Certifications



The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing - Google



Nobberman Soft-Skills Training - Jobberman Nigeria

Skills

Digital Marketing • Figma (Software) • HTML • Microsoft PowerPoint • Adobe Photoshop • Microsoft Word • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • React.js • Bootstrap